Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer 1950-1997 1970-1990
AFC 2019/004
419 items.
389 containers.
388 sound cassettes: analog.
1 sound tape reel (5 in.): analog.
1 folder (30 items).
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Nora Marks Dauenhauer, of Yakutat and Tlingit heritage, along with her husband Richard Dauenhauer, recorded hundreds of personal narratives during the 1960s to the 1980s. Nora was one of a group of Tlingit women who undertook language revitalization during the same period. The collection consists of interviews with Tlingit language speakers in Alaska. The bulk of the recordings were made between the 1960s to the 1980s, some in the 1950s, a few are copies of field recordings made by Frederica de Laguna (1950s) and John Swanton (1904). Through personal narratives, songs, and stories, these tradition bearers impart knowledge about inter-tribal relationships and relationships with outside communities, economic life, medicine, fishing, religious expression, and other aspects of community life.
Provenance
Alice Taff (executor); gift; 2019.
Custodial History
The Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer collection was transferred to Alice Taff and Kathy Kolkhorst Ruddy (English executor).
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Additional Guides
Finding aid for Dauenhauer Tlingit Oral Literature collection at Sealaska Heritage Institute.
Other Repositories
Sealaska Heritage Institute contains significant manuscript materials of Nora and Richard Daenhauer, as well as the Dauenhauer Tlingit Oral Literature collection of approximately 500 audio recordings on CD. There may be overlapping materials with AFC's collection.
Related Material
John R. Swanton collection of Tlingit cylinder recordings (AFC 1948/146)
Frederica de Laguna and Catharine McClellan Tlingit recordings, 1950 (AFC 1970/052)
Frederica de Laguna, Mary Jane Downs Lenz, and Catharine McClellan collection of Tlingit, Atna Athabaskan, and Southern Tutchone recordings, 1954 (AFC 1962/014)
Carol Beery Davis collection of Tlingit songs (AFC 1979/037)
Agnes Bellinger Tlingit collection, 1985 (AFC 1986/017)
Access and Restrictions
The Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical note
Born May 8, 1927, Nora Marks Dauenhauer was a Tlingit poet, writer, and Tlingit language scholar. Her husband, Richard Daunhauer, was an American linguist, professor, and poet, and became an advocate for the Tlingit language. From 2012 to 2014 Nora was the Alaska States Poet Laureate, and Richard was Poet Laureate of Alaska from 1981 to 1988. Nora and Richard recorded hundreds of personal narratives of Tlingit elders and others in the community. These recordings document Tlingit history, language, traditions, and subsistence through oral history, gatherings, and cultural programs. The Dauenhauers worked and were affiliated with Sealaska Heritage Institute (SHI) and published numerous books including coediting SHI's Classics of Tlingit Oral Literature series together.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of interviews with Tlingit language speakers in Alaska and recordings from Tlingit gatherings and events. The bulk of the recordings were made between the 1960s to the 1980s, some in the 1950s, a few are copies of field recordings made by Frederica de Laguna (1950s) and John Swanton (1904). Through personal narratives, songs, and stories, these tradition bearers impart knowledge about inter-tribal relationships and relationships with outside communities, economic life, medicine, fishing, religious expression, and other aspects of community life.
Arrangement
The Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Tlingit and English recordings, 1950-1997, (bulk 1970-1990)
Arranged according to the numbering system kept by the Dauenhauers, labeled on the tapes upon donation to AFC. This numbering is reflected in the Original Tape IDs.
The quotation marks in the item-level descriptions of contents indicate that the notes were drawn directly from the collector documentation.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Dauenhauer, Nora; Dauenhauer, Richard; Hammond, Austin; Marks, Johnny, 1943-2009; Paul, William L.; Thlunaut, Jennie, 1892-1986; Williams, Emma, 1898-; Williams, Frank, 1890-; Zuboff, Robert
Subjects
Tales.; Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Folklore.; Tlingit Indians--Music.; Tlingit language--Alaska.
Places
Alaska.
Form/Genre
Interviews.; Oral histories.; Personal narratives.; Songs.; Sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1. Tlingit and English recordings, ca. 1950-1997 Bulk: 1970-1990
  The collection consists of interviews with Tlingit language speakers in Alaska. The bulk of the recordings were made between 1960s to the 1980s, some in the 1950s, a few are copies of field recordings made by Frederica de Laguna (1950s) and John Swanton (1904). Through personal narratives, songs, and stories, these tradition bearers impart knowledge about inter-tribal relationships and relationships with outside communities, economic life, medicine, fishing, religious expression, and other aspects of community life. Descriptions, including speakers' names, moieties, crests, clans, and other descriptive information about the recordings come from documentation provided by donor.
  - Accompanying documentation to recordings, ca. 1950-1995, 1 folder (Box-folder 1/1)
    J-cards removed from cassette cases containing information about recordings' contents.
  - Robert Zuboff mosquito, ca. 1970-1974, Tape 1.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR001)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: unknown. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Dakl'aweidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: How mosquitos came to be.
  - Frank Johnson Strong Man, ca. 1970-1974, Tape 2.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR002)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Taakw K'wát'i. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Suktineidí (Kake). Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Story of the Strong Man.
  - Interview with Frank Dick, February 11, 1978, Tape 3.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR003)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Dick Sr. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Naakal.aan. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: L'ook (Coho). Speaker's Clan: L'uknax.ádi (Dry Bay). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Moving from one area to another.
  - Interview with Frank Dick, February 11, 1978, Tape 4.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR004)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Dick Sr. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Naakal.aan. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: L'ook (Coho). Speaker's Clan: L'uknax.ádi (Dry Bay). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Conversation, including Jenny White (Frank's Wife).
  - Interview with Willie Marks, 1968, Tape 10.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR005)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Crying for Jimmy Marks.
  - Jimmy Marks/original songs, December 30, 1971, Tape 10.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR006)
    Speaker's English name: Jimmy Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Original songs. Jenny Marks, Jessy Kasko, singing.
  - Interview with Jenny Marks, ca. 1970s, Tape 11.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR007)
    Speaker's English name: Jenny Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Xus.een; Kultuyáx Sée. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal);Talku (Devils Thumb Mtn). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska (probably). Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: The proper way to give someone a Tlingit name; sharing names. Jenny Marks talking about life and witchcraft.
  - Interviews with Tom Peters and Bert Dennis, September 1972, Tape 12.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR008)
    Speaker's English name: Tom Peters; Bert Dennis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Yeilnaawú; Aan Kadaxtseen. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven); Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown; Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Tuk.weidí; Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal). Father's Clan: Yanyeidí; unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Teslin Yukon; Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: The woman who married the bear continues, making medicine for love or for money. Migration, Taalkú, trouble in Tlingit; in Juneau the winds aren't strong; Skagway- angry place; Dakkaadáxdei- end of the road- Haines; Tsaxanx'aan- near Petersburg; Juneau is the same way; Chaak' Heenee; Chaak' Heenee á; Kaak'xwan; Geesan-aan; Laxach' T'aak.
  - Interview with Willie Marks, January 2, 1979, Tape 13.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR009)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Killer Whale story.
  - Celebration speech, 1982, Tape 14.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR010)
    Speaker's English name: Emma Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Seigeigé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal). Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Celebration speech, giving her geneology.
  - SNEP Raven Stories, April 4, 1995, Tape 16.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR011)
    Speaker's English name: Charlie Joseph. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaal.átk'. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: L'uknax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: SNEP. Description of contents: Raven and the Salmon Run.
  - Interview with J.B. Fawcett, October 3, 1972, Tape 19.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR012)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Story of Kaats' (a Teikweidí man).
  - Interview with A.P. Johnson, December 12, 1972, Tape 20.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR013)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Battle of Sitka.
  - Lonnie Houston and wife telling Glacier Bay story, undated, Tape 21.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR014)
    Speaker's English name: Lonnie Houston. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Takdeintaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Glacier Bay stories and songs by Lonnie Houston and his wife.
  - Interview with A.P. Johnson, undated, Tape 22.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR015)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Battle of Sitka and Kiks.ádi history.
  - Interview with Jimmy Marks, December 30, 1971, Tape 23.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR016)
    Speaker's English name: Jimmy Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Marks collection of Songs. Chookaneidí songs. Love song, Eagle hat song.
  - Interview with Alex Andrews, undated, Tape 24.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR017)
    Speaker's English name: Alex Andrews. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kooxíchx'. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kiks.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: X'ax'aa Hít, Shaká, Xaalgáash.
  - Interview with J.B. Fawcett, August 8, 1972, Tape 26.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR018)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Stories and Songs.
  - Interview with A.P. Johnson, undated, Tape 27.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR019)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Story of Kaakáa a Kiks.ádi man.
  - North Pass history, January 20, 1997, Tape 28.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR020)
    Speaker's English name: Andrew Johnny. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Deitxoon. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Cheech (Porpoise). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Narrative of Glacier Bay.
  - Mrs. Willard, Alice Lee, Jennie Thlunaut, Elizabeth David, 1970, Tape 29.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR021)
    Speaker's English name: Mrs. Willard, Alice Lee, Jennie Thlunaut, Elizabeth David. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shax'saani Kéek' (Jennie Thlunaut). Speaker's Moiety: Both Yéil and Ch'áak'. Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Songs form Haines.
  - Emma Ellis, 1954, Tape 30.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR022)
    Speaker's English name: Emma Ellis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaawat x'wás'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Yakutat, Alaska. Recorded by: de Laguna?. Description of contents: Chaatl Yaakw.
  - Esther Johnson, 1970, Tape 31.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR023)
    Speaker's English name: Esther Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xeitl (Thunderbird). Speaker's Clan: Shangukeidí (Dry Bay area?). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Naming of Lukaax.ádi houses on Alsek River.
  - David Kadashan, Jenny Marks, John Marks, October 6, 1974, Tape 32.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR024)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: David Kadashan, Jennie Marks, John Marks, Susie James (briefly) songs and conversation.
  - George Davis raven stories, April 1, 1973, Tape 33.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR025)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: White Raven and the Water; Modern Tlingit people, what to do and how to do it when recording/documenting Tlingit people.
  - Charlie Joseph Kaax'achgóok history, March 17, 1973, Tape 34.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR026)
    Speaker's English name: Charlie Joseph. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaal.átk'. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: L'uknax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Story of Kaax'achgóok.
  - Frank Williams interview, July 1973, Tape 35.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR027)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Williams. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Koodénahaa. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Gaanax.ádi (Ketchikan). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Ketchikan, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Frank Williaams and wife life stories.
  - Tebenkoff Bay Robert Zuboff, 1973, Tape 36.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR028)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Dakl'aweidí. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tebenkoff Bay life.
  - Aunty Jenny, Haines, July 6, 1974, Tape 37.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR029)
    Speaker's English name: Jenny Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Xus.een; Kultuyáx Sée. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal);Talku (Devils Thumb Mtn). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tlingit life with Jennie Marks.
  - Multiple speakers, 1974, Tape 38.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR030)
    Speaker's English name: Multiple speakers. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Multiple speakers. Speaker's Moiety: Multiple speakers. Speaker's Crest: Multiple crests. Speaker's Clan: Multiple clans. Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Alaska Methodist University. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Native Emphasis Week.
  - Austin Hammond, May 25, 1974, Tape 39.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR031)
    Speaker's English name: Austin Hammond. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Austin Hammond. Speaker's Moiety: Austin Hammond. Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi(Haines). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Alaska Native Brotherhood Juneau. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Song and dance practice.
  - Haines Dance Group with Marks Trail Dancers, July 5, 1974, Tape 40.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR032)
    Speaker's English name: Haines Dance Group with Marks Trail Dancers. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Multiple Singers. Speaker's Moiety: Both Yéil and Ch'áak'. Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Marks Trail Dancers). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Alaska Native Brotherhood Juneau. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Song and dance performance?
  - Tom Peters, August 29, 1973, Tape 41.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR033)
    Speaker's English name: Tom Peters. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Yeilnaawú. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: S'igeidí (Beaver). Father's Clan: Yanyeidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Teslin, Yukon Territory. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tom Peters, Teslin, Yukon.
  - Tom Peters, August 29, 1973, Tape 42.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR034)
    Speaker's English name: Tom Peters. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Yeilnaawú. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Tuk.weidí (Inland). Father's Clan: Yanyeidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Teslin, Yukon Territory. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tom Peters, stories of the Golden Lady and The Water Beetle named Hintayéeshi.
  - Tom Peters: the women who were captured by wolf, August 29, 1973, Tape 43.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR035)
    Speaker's English name: Tom Peters. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Yeilnaawú. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Tuk.weidí. Father's Clan: Yanyeidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Teslin, Yukon Territory. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Women who were captured by the Wolf.
  - Johnny Frazer, August 2, 1973, Tape 44.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR036)
    Speaker's English name: Johnny Frazer. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tinaa s'aatée. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: unknown. Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Champagne, Yukon. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Johnny Fraser, Bear Husband.
  - George Davis, March 13, 2008, Tape 45.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR037)